Preliminary Inventory of the Walter E. Monagan papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Walter E. Monagan papers
1945-1948
73037
Hoover Institution Archives
8 manuscript boxes (2.4 linear feet)
Reports, ordinances, proclamations, and legal opinions relating to political, economic, and legal aspects of governmental administration in Korea, and to repatriation of Japanese in Korea. Collection also available on microfilm (12 reels); microfilm is off-site.
Monagan, Walter E.
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1973.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternate Forms Available
Collection also available on microfilm (12 reels); microfilm is off-site.
Biographical Note
Legal adviser, United States Military Government in Korea, 1945-1948.
Scope and Content of Collection
Reports, ordinances, proclamations, and legal opinions relating to political, economic, and legal aspects of governmental administration in Korea, and to repatriation of Japanese in Korea.
United States. Army. Forces in Korea.; United States. Army. Forces, Pacific.; United States. Military Advisory Group to the Republic of Korea.; Military government.; Japan--History--Allied occupation, 1945-1952.; Korea--History--Allied occupation, 1945-1948.
- United States Army Military Government in Korea (USAMGIK) File, 1947-1948
  Scope and Contents note
  Selected legal opinions of the Department of Justice, USAMGIK, South Korean Interim Government activities.
  - 1947 (Box 1)
    - No. 23, August
    - No. 24, September
    - No. 25, October
    - No. 26, November
    - No. 27, December
  - 1948 (Box 2)
    - No. 28, January
    - No. 29, February
    - No. 30, March
    - No. 31, April
    - No. 32, May
    - No. 33, June
    - No. 34, July-August
    - No. 35, September-October
- Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers File, 1945-1946 (Box 3)
  Summation of non-military activities in Japan and Korea.
  - 1945
    - No. 1, September-October
    - No. 2, November
    - No. 3, December
  - 1946
    - No. 4, January
    - No. 5, February
    - No. 6, March
    - No. 7, April
    - No. 8, May
    - No. 9, June
- United States Army Forces, Pacific. Commander-in-Chief File, 1946-1947 (Box 4)
  Summation of United States Army Military Government activities in Korea.
  - 1946
    - No. 10, July
    - No. 11, August
    - No. 12, September
    - No. 13, October
    - No. 14, November
    - No. 15, December
  - 1947
    - No. 16, January
    - No. 17, February
    - No. 18, March
    - No. 19, April
    - No. 20, May
    - No. 21, June
    - No. 22, July
- USAMGIK, Headquarters. Foreign Affairs Section File, 1945
  Repatriation from September 25-December 31, 1945.
- Air Force Intelligence, Melbourne. Directorate of Air Force Intelligence File
  Korean place names.
- Department of State, Korea File, 1945-1948
  A report on political developments and economic resources, with selected documents.
- United States Army Forces in Korea, Headquarters File (Boxes 5-8)
  Laws, orders, ordinances, proclamations, etc. of the United States agencies in Korea.